<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Javascript on Toast 🍞]]></title><description><![CDATA[A blog about Javascript, Node and the Web]]></description><link>https://grantis.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:53:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[React + Memo]]></title><description><![CDATA[Memo]]></description><link>https://grantis.github.io/react/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grantis.github.io/react/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 22:12:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Memo&lt;/h1&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Node Version Manager]]></title><description><![CDATA[or Node Version Manager is the easiest way to have all your NodeJs projects working correctly and on the version they require. By using nvm…]]></description><link>https://grantis.github.io/nvm/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grantis.github.io/nvm/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 22:12:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;nvm&lt;/code&gt; or Node Version Manager is the easiest way to have all your NodeJs projects working correctly and on the version they require. By using nvm you no longer need to manage this dependency manually. Hooraa!! 🎉🎉🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Setup and Install&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you have Node installed. Run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;curl -o- https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nvm-sh/nvm/v0.35.2/install.sh | bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command uses curl to download the install script and pipe it into bash to run. nvm is cloned into &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;~/.nvm&lt;/code&gt; and will add nvm to your
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;~/.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;~/.profile&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;~/.bash_rc&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;~/.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; in order to run globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Automatically switch node versions 🚀&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;.nvmrc&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nvm-sh/nvm#nvmrc&quot;&gt;From &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;nvm&lt;/code&gt;’s usage guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can create a .nvmrc file containing a node version number (or any other string that nvm understands; see nvm —help for details) in the project root directory (or any parent directory). Afterwards, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;nvm use&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;nvm install&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;nvm exec&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;nvm run&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;nvm which&lt;/code&gt; will use the version specified in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;.nvmrc&lt;/code&gt; file if no version is supplied on the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, to make nvm default to the latest 5.9 release, the latest LTS version, or the latest node version for the current directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ echo “5.9” &gt; .nvmrc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ echo “lts/*” &gt; .nvmrc # to default to the latest LTS version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ echo “node” &gt; .nvmrc # to default to the latest version
Then when you run nvm:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ nvm use
Found ‘/path/to/project/.nvmrc’ with version &amp;#x3C;5.9&gt;
Now using node v5.9.1 (npm v3.7.3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nvm-sh/nvm#install--update-script&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;nvm&lt;/code&gt; on Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What, How, Why Shell 🐚]]></title><description><![CDATA[Introduction Contents: what is a shell types of shells how to use a shell What the Shell? If you work with computers, or if you have ever…]]></description><link>https://grantis.github.io/shell/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grantis.github.io/shell/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 22:12:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;index.md#what-the-shell&quot;&gt;what is a shell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;index.md#Windows-Linux-Mac-and-Shells&quot;&gt;types of shells&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;index.md#great-so-how-do-i-start&quot;&gt;how to use a shell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What the Shell?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you work with computers, or if you have ever seen the matrix movies you’re probably aware of a strange computer program known as a command line interface (CLI). This intermidating program, with its blinking green cursor against a  black background was, in the old times, the only real way people interfaced with computers. The history of the CLI is a facinating story and it’s full of various decisions along the way that have come to make the modern CLI what it is today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is the shell? A shell is a CLI, as you might have guessed, and it comes with a range of features and utilities that the user can use to do stuff with the computer that might be harder or even impossible to do with a convential GUI style application. The shell can create files and folders, run programs and even connect to other computers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Windows, Linux, Mac and Shells&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that is useful to know is what kind of shell you have available to you. As mentioned earlier shells come in all kinds of styles. Different shells have been developed alongside different operating systems and you could right a whole book on the differences between them. For brevity however there is two main kinds of shells, Windows based and Unix based which include linux and macOS. These shells just have different commands for the same actions such as creating folders or changing directories but largely enable users to access the same programs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Great, so how do I start?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your running macOS or Linux, you can use terminal app. By default you have access to the bash shell. This is the out the box shell. When you open it up you’ll see your root directory. From here you can practily do what ever you want. If you’re someone who wants to store files you can download the AWS cli and upload terebytes of data, if you work with images you can use a bash script to automate editing files in batches and if you’re a developer you can setup servers, download software and deploy apps. Theres alot that can be down here. To start&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>